Guide to the George Wells Beadle Papers 1908-1981
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Subject Files, 1961-1968
  - Genetics Society of America, Inc., Thomas Hunt Morgan Centennial Symposium, University of Kentucky, September 17-20, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - George Washington Memorial Foundation; re: proposed University of the United States, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Gustavus Adolphus College, 1963-1968 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - High school representatives of school papers, interview with George Wells Beadle, January 19, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Illinois, University of, Gehrmann Lecture for 1965 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Illinois, University of, presentation of honorary degree to George Wells Beadle, June 15, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Jefferson, Thomas, Research Center, 1965-1968 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Junior Achievement of Chicago, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Kansas State University, John Frazier, 1964-1968 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Kennedy, John F., College, Wahoo, Nebraska (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Leadership Council (established to implement "Summit Agreement" on housing in August 1966) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Lindegren, Carl; Lindegren, Gertrude (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, International Symposium in the Life Sciences, address by George Wells Beadle, December 3, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Medical College of Virginia, Stoneburner Lectures (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Mendel, Gregor J., centennial programs (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Mendelism, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - National Committee on Tithing in Investment, 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - National Science Museum, Cleveland, Ohio (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - National Science Teachers Association, 1962-1968 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, November 1962- (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Outside comment on announced retirement in 1968 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Piedmont University Center of North Carolina (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Planned Parenthood; world population, 1962-1967 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Prairie Grouse Committee (sponsored by Illinois Chapter of the Nature Conservancy), 1966 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Rockhurst College (Kansas City, Missouri) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Ross, James G. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Science Clubs of Cary-Grove Community High School and Crystal Lake Community High School (Illinois), 1961-1966 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Scientific Advisory Board of N. W. Ayer & Son, Inc., 1961- (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Singleton, W. Ralph; Singleton, Katya, 1961-1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Society of Mayflower Descendents in the State of Illinois, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Southwest Center for Advanced Studies (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University, dedication, William F. Herrin Hall and Laboratories, George Wells Beadle speaker, November 30, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Test-Ban Treaty, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - United Educators, Inc. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - U. S. Air Force, Operation alias "Cool School," 1963-1967 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - U. S. Committee to Advise Congress on Certain National Problems Involving Scientific Research (named October 1964) (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - U. S. National Institutes of Health, National Advisory General Medical Sciences Council, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - U. S. Science-Engineering Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Wabash College, George Wells Beadle honorary degree, December 3, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Wisconsin, University of (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence, A-E Book of poems entitled "50 poems" by Cornel Adam, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, F-R (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, L (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, S-Z (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Material from "Symposium on Non-Equilibrium Thermodynamics, Variational Techniques and Stability," May 17-19, 1965, University of Chicago. Sponsored jointly by the Universite Libre de Bruxelles, Belgium, and the General Motors Research Lab (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence on rejected invitations, A-Z (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Invitations accepted, campus (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Invitations accepted, off campus (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Invitations rejected, campus (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Invitations regretted, off campus (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Invitations regretted, campus (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - George Wells Beadle, letters of congratulations on election to Chancellorship received, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Material regarding "On Early Learning"; enclosures on Montessori; newspaper article (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - George Wells Beadle, requests for autographs received (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - George Wells Beadle, personal letters, A-Z (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - George Wells Beadle, publication correspondence (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - George Wells Beadle, "Regrets A-K, 1961-1968" (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - George Wells Beadle, "Regrets L-Z, 1961-1968" (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Speaking engagement at Hyde Park Business and Professional Association, January 28, 1964, notes, background material, and copy of speech including much miscellaneous data on University of Chicago and Hyde Park (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - George and Muriel Beadle, publication materials, newspaper clippings, correspondence, mailing lists (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "Civic Dinner to Honor Mr. and Mrs. George Wells Beadle, July 9, 1968, Pick-Congress Hotel," letters of thank, clippings, invitations, seating plan, program/menu, news release and partial guest list (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "Civic Dinner to Honor Mr. and Mrs. George Wells Beadle, July 9, 1968, Pick-Congress Hotel," invitations, correspondence, press releases, seating plan, guest lists (Box 24A, Folder 1-5)
  - "Civic Dinner to Honor Mr. and Mrs. George Wells Beadle, July 9, 1968, Pick-Congress Hotel," text of speech by Robert E. Brooker, "Civic Dinner to Honor Mr. and Mrs. George Wells Beadle, July 9, 1968, Pick-Congress Hotel," text of speech by Mary Ward "Civic Dinner to Honor Mr. and Mrs. George Wells Beadle, July 9, 1968, Pick-Congress Hotel," text of remarks by Muriel Beadle "Civic Dinner to Honor Mr. and Mrs. George Wells Beadle, July 9, 1968, Pick-Congress Hotel," text of remarks by George W. Beadle (Box 24A, Folder 6)
  - Muriel Beadle, University business correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
  - Muriel Beadle, University business correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Muriel Beadle, personal correspondence, A-M (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Muriel Beadle, personal correspondence, N-Z (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Muriel Beadle, publications and papers (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Telegrams, March 16, 1966 (Beadle's 5th anniversary as president) (Box 26)
  - Photograph of George and Muriel Beadle, March 1966, for bookjacket of The Language of Life (original in Archival Photofiles) (Box 26)
  - Photograph of George Wells Beadle with hotel clerk, n.d. (original in Archival Photofiles) (Box 26)
  - Fillmore High School Science Club, Fillmore, California, Honorary Membership, letter and certificate, June 20, 1961 (Box 26)
  - Eleven calendar books, 1962-1969 (Box 26)
  - The Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, "D. F. Jones Medal" to George Wells Beadle, September 14, 1972 (Box 27)
  - Medal with King Olaf V of Norway on one side, cross on reverse, on red ribbon striped with blue and white (Box 27)
  - Dickinson College Award For Distinguished Contributions through Biology, 1967 (Box 27)
  - Honorary doctorate from Syracuse University, 1968 (Box 27)
  - Photo album of George Wells Beadle's trip to Dickinson College to accept his award, 1967 (Box 27)
  - Plaque, "Distinguished Lecturer," 1981 (Box 27)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1908-1946 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1954-1956 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Offprints of articles and reports by or about GWB, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Material on George Wells Beadle's retirement from University of Chicago Presidency, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Material relating to Shah of Iran visit (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of George Wells Beadle and Muriel Beadle, 1966-1968 (originals in Archival Photofiles) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - George Wells Beadle retirement materials, including lectures, functions, etc. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Edward Levi inauguration mementos (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Hannah Gray inauguration mementos, photos (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - John Wilson inauguration mementos, photos (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Amateur theatricals at the University of Chicago, notes and clippings (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Edward Levi as Attorney General, clippings (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Clippings related to the Beadles' arrival in Chicago (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - George Wells Beadle administration materials, 1962-1965 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - George Wells Beadle biographical information, pre-1961 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Materials produced by the Beadles concerning Hyde Park and the university of Chicago (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - George Wells Beadle, Honorary Doctor of Humane Letters, University of Chicago, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - George Wells Beadle, miscellaneous notes and correspondence, on college and graduate funding at the University of Chicago; John Wilson's "Temples on the River Nile Project"; University of Chicago Alumni and Faculty working in Washington, D. C. for federal government; South East Chicago Commission, 1961; "Questions" concerning the College at the University of Chicago (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago bulletins related to George Wells Beadle appearances (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous George Wells Beadle speeches, notes, etc. George Wells Beadle, thesis, University of Nebraska, 1927 F. D. Keim and George Wells Beadle, "Prairie Hay in Nebraska," 1926 Muriel Beadle, "A Nice, Neat Operation" (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Honorary degrees (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Honorary degrees (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Honorary degrees (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Honorary degrees (Box 33, Folder 4)